<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jay M. Patel</title>
    <link>http://jaympatel.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jay M. Patel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Jay M. Patel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jaympatel.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I am a fullstack software developer and an internet marketer working on web scraping, natural language processing, data mining and content marketing.
I also design and implement machine learning based models at a startup Specrom Analytics as their principal data scientist.
In my free time, I volunteer in dangs district in India to assist tribal community in building homes, getting clean water and sanitation. I also write about issues pertaining to these issues at various outlets as well as blog about them here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural language processing (NLP): Text Vectorization and Bag of Words Approach</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2019/02/natural-language-processing-nlp-text-vectorization-and-bag-of-words-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2019/02/natural-language-processing-nlp-text-vectorization-and-bag-of-words-approach/</guid>
      <description>Let us consider a simple task of classifying a given email into spam or not spam. As you might have already guessed, this is an example of a simple binary classification problem with target or label values being 0 or 1, within the larger field of supervised machine learning (ML).
However, we still need to convert non-numerical text contained in emails into numerical features which can be fed into a ML algorithm of our choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Data Science Interview Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2019/02/top-data-science-interview-questions-and-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2019/02/top-data-science-interview-questions-and-answers/</guid>
      <description>Machine Learning Basics 1. What is machine learning? Machine learning (ML) is a field of computer science that gives computer systems the ability to progressively improve performance on a specific task aka learn with data without being explicitly programmed. Taking a 50,000 ft view, we want to model a given dataset either to make predictions or we want a model to describe a given dataset to gain valuable insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started with Git and Github in Under 10 Minutes</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2018/11/get-started-with-git-and-github-in-under-10-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 08:59:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2018/11/get-started-with-git-and-github-in-under-10-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Git is probably the most popular version control system being used right now, and if you have any experience with other version control systems like subversion than it&amp;rsquo;s strongly recommended that you go through this section since lot of concepts from other systems don&amp;rsquo;t directly translate to Git.
Git Basics You can create a local Git repository on your computer by either:
 Clone an existing Git repository from a remote repository on internet (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/cv/</guid>
      <description>jay@jaympatel.com | jaypatel87@gmail.com
LINKEDIN: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jay-m-patel-engg
HOMEPAGE: http://www.jaympatel.com
Click here for latest PDF version
PROFILE:
 Data scientist with over five year&amp;rsquo;s experience in data analytics, machine learning, statistics and text mining.
 I have coauthored 1 book, 10 papers, 26 conference presentations and am passionate about explaining data science to non-technical business audiences.
 Frequent speaker at data science events hosted by Federal community of practice (CoP) as part of DigitalGov initiative.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>