<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Jay M. Patel</title>
    <link>http://jaympatel.com/categories/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Jay M. Patel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Jay M. Patel</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://jaympatel.com/categories/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction data enrichment based on email addresses and domain names</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2020/08/introduction-data-enrichment-based-on-email-addresses-and-domain-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2020/08/introduction-data-enrichment-based-on-email-addresses-and-domain-names/</guid>
      <description>Data enrichment is a general term to denote any processes which enhance and enrich your existing database with additional information which can be used to drive your business goals such as marketing, sales and lead generation, customer relations by targeted outreach and preventing customer churn.
Plainly speaking, all you are doing is going out to a third party data vendor and fetching additional data based on some common key. One of the most keys for data enrichment is searching based on email address or company&amp;rsquo;s domain address.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to do full text searching in Python using Whoosh library</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2020/08/how-to-do-full-text-searching-in-python-using-whoosh-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2020/08/how-to-do-full-text-searching-in-python-using-whoosh-library/</guid>
      <description>Full text searching with fast indexing is essential to go through large quantities of text in Pandas dataframes to power your data science workflows. Traditionally, we can use a full text search engine databases like Elasticsearch, Apache Solr or Amazon cloudsearch for this; however, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty impractical to do that for one off requirements or when working with only few GBs of data.
In that case, you can simply load your text into Pandas dataframe, and use regex to perform the search as shown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create pdf documents in python using FPDF library</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2020/08/how-to-create-pdf-documents-in-python-using-fpdf-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2020/08/how-to-create-pdf-documents-in-python-using-fpdf-library/</guid>
      <description>PDF files are ubiquitous in our daily life and it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to spend few minutes to learn how to programmatically generate it in Python.
In this tutorial, we will take structured data in JSON and convert that into a pdf. Ideally, pdfs contain text paragraphs, hyperlinks and images, so we will work with a dataset containing all of that for better real world experience.
Firstly, let us fetch the data from a publicly available API containing scraped news articles from past 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top data science interview questions and answers</title>
      <link>http://jaympatel.com/2019/02/top-data-science-interview-questions-and-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jaympatel.com/2019/02/top-data-science-interview-questions-and-answers/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning Basics 1. What is machine learning? Machine learning (ML) is a field of computer science that gives computer systems the ability to progressively improve performance on a specific task aka learn with data without being explicitly programmed. Taking a 50,000 ft view, we want to model a given dataset either to make predictions or we want a model to describe a given dataset to gain valuable insights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>